<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Ni</title>
    <description>My personal site.</description>
    <link>http://danielni.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://danielni.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top 10 Albums of 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;julia-holter-have-you-in-my-wilderness&quot;&gt;10. Julia Holter: Have You In My Wilderness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.albumoftheyear.org/album/2015/36433-have-you-in-my-wilderness.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Feel You, Lucette Stranded on the Island, Sea Calls Me Home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OERixQR-hxY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tobias-jesso-jr-goon&quot;&gt;9. Tobias Jesso Jr.: Goon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tobiasjessojr.com/newimages/packshot2.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: How Could You Babe, Without You, Hollywood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uu1Ko02P7vk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sophie-product&quot;&gt;8. SOPHIE: PRODUCT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.spin.com/files/2015/09/sophie-product-new-album.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Bipp, Hard, Vyzee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/234530246&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;drake-if-youre-reading-this-its-too-late&quot;&gt;7. Drake: If You’re Reading This It’s Too Late&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/news/58558/46ceb4fa.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: 10 Bands, Know Yourself, Jungle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/79AR0VC5wCA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chvrches-every-open-eye&quot;&gt;6. Chvrches: Every Open Eye&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.pastemagazine.com/www/articles/36804-every-open-eye.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Leave a Trace, Clearest Blue, High Enough to Carry You Over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/214956238&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kendrick-lamar-to-pimp-a-butterfly&quot;&gt;5. Kendrick Lamar: To Pimp a Butterfly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2015/3/11/1426099817173/f1efb3f4-9a6d-4f78-8ca8-594ab646d198-bestSizeAvailable.jpeg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: King Kunta, Alright, The Blacker the Berry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z-48u_uWMHY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grimes-art-angels&quot;&gt;4. Grimes: Art Angels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.albumoftheyear.org/album/43091-art-angels.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Flesh Without Blood, Artangels, REALiTi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tv9YoYCKNoE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;young-thug-barter-6&quot;&gt;3. Young Thug: Barter 6&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.rapgenius.com/86f73affb60610652707de695fa3c994.640x640x1.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: With That (feat. Duke), Check, Knocked Off (feat. Birdman)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RAzzv6Ks9nc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jamie-xx-in-colour&quot;&gt;2. Jamie xx: In Colour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.complex.com/complex/image/upload/t_article_image/incolour_qrufwh.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Gosh, Loud Noises (feat. Romy), I Know There’s Gonna Be (Good Times) [feat. Young Thug &amp;amp; Popcaan]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TP9luRtEqjc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sufjan-stevens-carrie--lowell&quot;&gt;1. Sufjan Stevens: Carrie &amp;amp; Lowell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/news/58935/dbfa1978.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placeholder text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Should Have Known Better, Fourth of July, The Only Thing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/195330662&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 19:10:19 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielni.github.io/2015/12/20/top-albums-of-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielni.github.io/2015/12/20/top-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lessons Learned From a New Grad Job Search</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re like me, you’re one of thousands of college seniors around the country looking for a job in the tech industry after graduation. After five grueling months, my process is finally over, and although I’m extremely happy with how things turned out, there are definitely some things I wish I knew before I began the process in August. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have some experience interviewing in the tech industry, you should already be familiar with the standard advice: work on personal projects and try to land an internship to bolster your resume, brush up on data structures and algorithms for the interview, practice going through coding questions on a whiteboard, and research the company you’re interviewing with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I wanted to share some tips about the job search process that you don’t normally hear about, tailored specifically for new grads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/job_interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;relevant xkcd&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-early&quot;&gt;1. Start early.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many of the larger companies – Google, Facebook and Microsoft in particular – start interviewing for new grad positions in early August. They fill these spots on a rolling basis, but since these companies are so big, they should be hiring for a long time, right? Before I started my applications, I spent some time studying up on algorithms to get ready because I thought that they would never stop hiring, so it wouldn’t matter if I applied a few weeks or even months down the road. I learned the hard way that this isn’t the case. By the time I was ready to apply to Facebook, sometime in early October, they had already filled all of their spots for new grads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be an extreme case, but it does make sense why these companies start so early. It takes a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; long time to go through online coding tests, schedule phone interviews, plan for on site interviews and wait for feedback from recruiters. Before you know it, two months have passed and all you have to show for it is two phone interviews. My advice is don’t wait. Even if you don’t feel ready to interview, apply anyways so you can get on a company’s radar before it’s too late. If it turns out you really do need more time after landing an interview, ask for it then, since they (usually) can’t refuse a candidate who’s already in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stay-organized&quot;&gt;2. Stay organized.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re some kind of interviewing guru, you’ll likely be applying to dozens of different companies. This is why I recommend keeping a spreadsheet of all the places you’ve applied to. Personally, my spreadsheet listed all the companies I was interested in, ordered in tiers, where each tier of companies was separated by the next tier in order of personal preference. In the spreadsheet, I also kept track of the date applied, date of response (if any), any contacts at the company that I knew, any miscellaneous notes about that company’s hiring process, and a list of questions that I was asked if I received an interview. I was able to refer back to this spreadsheet over and over again throughout the semester to make sure I was keeping all of my applications straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tier ranking of companies also helped me plan the order I would apply. For instance, I tried to apply to companies in the lower tiers first so I could get more comfortable with interviewing before I talked to places where I badly wanted to work. Of course, this comes with the caveat from number 1 in that you still should apply to all the companies on your list as early as possible, or else you run the risk of missing out on an awesome company completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apply-through-all-available-avenues&quot;&gt;3. Apply through all available avenues.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can land an interview from almost anywhere. If a company is at your school’s career fair, great! Head over there and get your resume in the pile. As long as you haven’t failed out of all of your classes, you should be able to at least land an on campus interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a company isn’t at your school, it’s best if you can get a referral from someone you know inside the company, since your resume can then bypass all the standard filters. If you don’t know anyone, utilize your LinkedIn connections and reach out to any alumni from your school that might work there. Don’t be afraid to ask for a referral; they are probably more than happy to help out, since they were once in your situation too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all else fails, don’t be afraid to just apply online at a company’s website. I’ve heard it said that it’s pointless to do this, since your resume will just get lost in the ether of desperate new grads, but I’ve personally had a pretty good response rate, both positive and negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-get-discouraged&quot;&gt;4. Don’t get discouraged.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might often hear about how there’s a shortage of talent in the tech industry, and this is probably true, although I don’t claim to know enough about the industry to go into detail. However, I do know that new grad positions at the “hot” tech companies are extremely competitive. Unfortunately, it seems like every Computer Science major wants to work at Uber, Airbnb, Pinterest, or any of the hip unicorns that are experiencing massive growth right now. While these companies are growing, they obviously can’t afford to hire every single new grad, and so they basically get their pick of the best and brightest. If you aren’t able to get a job at any of these companies, don’t get down on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of awesome tech companies in the Bay Area, Seattle and New York. Chances are you haven’t even begun to scratch the surface on everything that’s out there. Just like college applications, don’t just focus on the big names; there are tons of hidden gems out there that may turn out to be the best fit for you. It’s not the end of the world if you don’t work at the coolest company at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-count-on-getting-feedback&quot;&gt;5. Don’t count on getting feedback.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all the failed interviews I’ve had (and there have been many), not once has a company provided specific feedback afterwards. This is understandable, since they have basically nothing to gain and a lot to lose by increasing the chances of a discrimination lawsuit. From the candidate’s perspective, it really would be nice to hear what went wrong and what they could do to improve for next time. I would suggest asking more vague questions like “Which interviews went well and which didn’t?” but don’t take it personally if you don’t get an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buy-a-whiteboard-and-practice-with-a-friend&quot;&gt;6. Buy a whiteboard and practice with a friend.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one seems kind of obvious, but it makes a huge difference. Unfortunately, we live in a world where we have to write code on a whiteboard to get a job, so you might as well get used to it since it’s completely different from typing at a computer. Practice walking through problems with a friend and take turns asking each other questions. Explain your thinking as you go and try to simulate as realistic an environment as possible, because it’s probably unlike anything you’ve done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relax&quot;&gt;7. Relax.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s really tough at first, since it seems like your entire future hinges on you getting that job at Google or Uber. Still, one of the best things you can do to prepare for an interview is just relax. If you’re nervous or stressed out, it’ll make it that much harder to think clearly during the interview, and as a result you won’t perform at your best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does get better with time. In August and September, I was so nervous before (and during) my interviews that I could barely think straight. By the end, a few months later, I was so used to interviewing that it fortunately didn’t phase me anymore. I don’t think it’s a coincidence that I ended up doing better on my later interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. Obviously, you should still follow the standard advice and buy &lt;em&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/em&gt; and go through all of those questions. I was lucky enough to land a job at one of my top tier companies, and hopefully, these tips will help you do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 19:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielni.github.io/2015/12/20/lessons-learned-from-a-new-grad-job-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielni.github.io/2015/12/20/lessons-learned-from-a-new-grad-job-search/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Top 10 Albums of 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Honestly, 2014 seemed like kind of a down year for music. Don’t get me wrong, there have been some great and innovative records this year, but overall, it doesn’t feel as if there have been any potential “classics”, save for maybe D’Angelo’s surprise comeback album. I feel like this is partially because of the absurd number of stadium-status artists who came out with albums last year, including Kanye West, Beyoncé, Arcade Fire, Justin Timberlake, Daft Punk, Drake, and more, and although this year saw some big releases from Taylor Swift, Coldplay, Skrillex, Nicki Minaj and U2 among others, nothing has felt quite as earth-shattering. Nevertheless, here’s a list of my favorite albums this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;st-vincent-st-vincent&quot;&gt;10. St. Vincent: St. Vincent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ilovestvincent.com/wp-2014-images/stv-600.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of artists have tried to tackle the topic of the effect of technology on our everyday lives to varying degrees of success, but Annie Clark succeeds both because of and in spite of her weirdness. Call it pretentious if you want, but weird and foreboding has also never been so much fun. There’s “Birth in Reverse”, which tries to inject some life into mundane everyday routines, and “Digital Witness”, probably the catchiest song ever written about the perils of the digital age. All in all, it’s just more of St. Vincent being St. Vincent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Rattlesnake, Digital Witness, Severed Crossed Fingers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/128164610&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iceage-plowing-into-the-field-of-love&quot;&gt;9. Iceage: Plowing Into the Field of Love&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bd/Iceage_Plowing_Into_the_Field_of_Love_Album_Cover.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I have no idea what Elias Rønnenfelt is saying half the time, but that just makes it so much cooler when you can hear him bellow things like “I do not repent / I keep pissing against the moon”. Iceage have completely expanded their sound since their last LP, &lt;em&gt;You’re Nothing&lt;/em&gt;, incorporating elements of post-punk, goth rock and even classic country, adding a barrage of guitars, strings and keyboards along the way. Though still obviously influenced by classic post-punk bands like Joy Division, Iceage have discovered a sound that is uniquely theirs on this record while still remaining super badass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: The Lord’s Favorite, Abundant Living, Against the Moon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/roB4hRdLlas&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;caribou-our-love&quot;&gt;8. Caribou: Our Love&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.mergerecords.com/stuff/contentmgr/files/6/b84507c69d3e9ba4fc4d9c3ec0d16ae1/image/_resized/10_700_700_488_caribou_ourlove_900.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;Our Love&lt;/em&gt; danceable? When the synths start blasting at full volume about halfway through “Can’t Do Without You”, it’s hard not to keep your head bobbing along. On the other hand, tracks like “Second Chance” play with beautiful melodies but are largely devoid of percussion or bass. Dan Snaith’s take on psychedelic synth pop is unique in that its purpose isn’t to light up dance floors; rather, it experiments with catchy rhythms to project the spotlight onto its themes of love and melancholy. The record overall is more mature, more sophisticated, and more self-aware than any of its predecessors. If you do decide to play it on the dance floor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j755GoKSrUE#t=3516&quot;&gt;remember to bring the balloons.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Can’t Do Without You, All I Ever Need, Second Chance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/152480774&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-war-on-drugs-lost-in-the-dream&quot;&gt;7. The War on Drugs: Lost in the Dream&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://assets.rollingstone.com/assets/images/album_review/51v5n3xx4sl-1395334192.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard the latter half of this album described as like a modern Bob Dylan. True, Adam Granduciel’s voice is the closest thing to a young Dylan’s this side of The Tallest Man on Earth, but I don’t think Dylan ever constructed a soundscape quite like the ones that comprise &lt;em&gt;Lost in the Dream&lt;/em&gt;. The songwriting is patient, as on tracks like “The Haunting Idle” which literally seem to idle for minutes at a time. But the payoff is always there, as evidenced by the transition into the release of “Burning”, or that moment in “In Reverse” when the grand parade finally arrives. No longer just that guy in Kurt Vile’s band, Granduciel has come into his own, creating an album that is both intimate and sprawling, about both loving and disappearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Eyes to the Wind, Lost in the Dream, In Reverse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/59mDoc8vZj0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dangelo-and-the-vanguard-black-messiah&quot;&gt;6. D’Angelo and the Vanguard: Black Messiah&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.pitchfork.com/news/57870/4425c018.jpeg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D’Angelo sure picked the perfect time to emerge from his shell, huh? Though this follow-up to his classic &lt;em&gt;Voodoo&lt;/em&gt; has been 14 years in the making, it manages to completely live up to the hype, and then some. There are so many subtle flourishes throughout &lt;em&gt;Black Messiah&lt;/em&gt;, and you can tell that D’Angelo really took the time to make sure every intricate detail was perfect. Just listen to the jazzy horns and Chic-like guitar on “Sugah Daddy” or the uncontrollable basss guitar in “1000 Deaths” to get an idea of how every aspect of every song was deliberated to perfection. Yeah, it took 14 years, but those were 14 years well spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: 1000 Deaths, Sugah Daddy, Another Life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/181260617&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-the-jewels-run-the-jewels-2&quot;&gt;5. Run the Jewels: Run the Jewels 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.complex.com/complex/image/upload/t_article_image/hjb5iy8uunz60cd1a8qr.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that this album was created before the spread of civil unrest toward the end of the year just shows how ahead of the curve Killer Mike and El-P are. Hearing Mike and El rap about the hypocrisy of the police and “the man behind the man behind the man behind the throne”, it’s hard not to consider this album as the face of a movement. But it’s not just the underlying politics that make this album so great. From the futuristic bombast of the “Oh My Darling Don’t Cry” beat to Travis Barker’s hyperactive percussion on “All Due Respect”, &lt;em&gt;RTJ2&lt;/em&gt; manages to sound daring and exceedingly effortless at the same time. All these guys have done is create an extremely timely record that’s still guaranteed to pump you up. Not bad for a couple of 40-somethings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Oh My Darling Don’t Cry, Early, Angel Duster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/173640008&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-nothings-here-and-nowhere-else&quot;&gt;4. Cloud Nothings: Here and Nowhere Else&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/41NYyfjNZjL.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of moving forward on &lt;em&gt;Here and Nowhere Else&lt;/em&gt;, despite Dylan Baldi’s claims to the contrary. For one, the band is less rough around the edges and more polished in their brand of noisy post-punk, both in terms of the tightness of the production and the painful beauty of Baldi’s songwriting. This happens to be one of those cases where a lo-fi band sheds a lot of the harshness of their sound and their music improves because of it. Each track just feels well put together with catchy melodies, invigorating guitar riffs, and sonic progressions that climax at precisely the right moments. Sometimes, even for a band with this aesthetic, prettier is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Now Hear In, No Thoughts, I’m Not Part of Me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/131156646&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sun-kil-moon-benji&quot;&gt;3. Sun Kil Moon: Benji&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.albumoftheyear.org/album/2014/12003-benji.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Kozalek may be an asshole, but you can almost forgive him for it after hearing about all the crap that’s happened in his life. Relatives die from aerosol can explosions, friends drop dead from sudden aneurysms, and he feels bad about punching a kid in elementary school. The magic of &lt;em&gt;Benji&lt;/em&gt; is that even though these stories are so personal and littered with specific details, they somehow still feel relatable. Maybe it’s the instrumentation, which remains mostly sparse and bare, drawing more attention to his rambling delivery of the lyrics. Or maybe it’s the fact that his descriptions make it so easy to project his characters onto people in our own lives. Either way, this is probably the best Panera Bread advertisement you’ll ever hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Carissa, Micheline, Ben’s My Friend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/wlFZE-rmTZQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-dress-well-what-is-this-heart&quot;&gt;2. How to Dress Well: What is This Heart?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.albumoftheyear.org/album/2014/14685-what-is-this-heart.jpg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his latest effort, Tom Krell manages to capture the sincere sentiment from &lt;em&gt;Love Remains&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Total Loss&lt;/em&gt; while expanding on his lo-fi R&amp;amp;B aesthetic to make it grander than ever. The results are gratifying, to say the least. Just listen to the swelling strings of “Pour Cyril”, which sound like they came straight from the soundtrack of the newest action-adventure epic, to get an idea of the scale of this project. Krell’s angelic voice is put to much better use, emerging as the focal point rather than blending into a barrage of synthesizers. Phrased as a question, the title of &lt;em&gt;What is This Heart?&lt;/em&gt; sounds tentative and unsure, but the boldness with which the album progresses proves that it is anything but.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: What You Wanted, Words I Don’t Remember, Precious Love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/sbOCLEIKZOo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-estate-atlas&quot;&gt;1. Real Estate: Atlas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn4.pitchfork.com/news/54116/d9f36f89.jpeg&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px !important&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who said guitar bands are on their way out? There’s a certain refinement to Matt Mondanile’s riffs that evoke a powerful sense of nostalgia while still being as satisfying as the most technically difficult of solos. It’s this nostalgia that Real Estate is constantly mining, and even though they decide to stay in the suburbs for their latest full length, they’re cruising around with a greater sense of responsibility and knowledge of the world around them. They’ve perfected the uneasy wistfulness that was starting to transpire on &lt;em&gt;Days&lt;/em&gt;, and for a bunch of suburban white kids, it’s amazing how profound their music is. “Do I sound insincere?” Martin Courtney asks on “The Bend”. We could insist on telling him no, but ultimately it wouldn’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standout tracks&lt;/strong&gt;: Had to Hear, Talking Backwards, Crime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/130704492&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 02:25:19 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielni.github.io/2014/12/18/top-albums-of-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielni.github.io/2014/12/18/top-albums-of-2014/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interactive Countries and Regions on a JavaScript Map</title>
        <description>&lt;head&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://www.google.com/jsapi&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
	google.load(&quot;visualization&quot;, &quot;1&quot;, {packages:[&quot;geochart&quot;]});
	google.setOnLoadCallback(drawRegionsMap);

	function drawRegionsMap() {

		var data = google.visualization.arrayToDataTable([
			[&#39;Country&#39;, &#39;Popularity&#39;],
			[&#39;Germany&#39;, 200],
			[&#39;United States&#39;, 300],
			[&#39;Brazil&#39;, 400],
			[&#39;Canada&#39;, 500],
			[&#39;France&#39;, 600],
			[&#39;RU&#39;, 700]
			]);

		var options = {};

		var chart = new google.visualization.GeoChart(document.getElementById(&#39;regions_div&#39;));

		chart.draw(data, options);
	}
	&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most difficult challenges I had while developing a working prototype of Atlas was figuring out the best way to obtain clickable, colorful countries and regions on a world map using JavaScript. I’d never really worked with any kind of map or location API before, so I had to do a lot of research to figure out which option best fit my needs. There are a lot of mapping libraries and frameworks out there, and it can be hard to parse through the different options for a task like this. So, in this post, I’ll summarize the different technologies I experimented with, along with some specific recommendations based on what exactly each one seems to be best built for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heres-how-the-basic-profile-page-for-atlashttpwwwmyatlasme-ended-up-looking-each-user-can-choose-their-own-countries-and-regions-and-style-their-map-dynamically&quot;&gt;Here’s how the basic profile page for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myatlas.me&quot;&gt;Atlas&lt;/a&gt; ended up looking. Each user can choose their own countries and regions and style their map dynamically.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/map_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Basic profile page for Atlas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-geochartshttpsdevelopersgooglecomchartinteractivedocsgallerygeochart&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/chart/interactive/docs/gallery/geochart&quot;&gt;Google Geocharts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predictably, my first thought for some kind of map-based API was Google Maps, so I did a bit of digging to see how individual regions on a map could be styled. As it turned out, the easiest way to obtain the data for country borders and other geographic data was by using the Geocharts in the Google Charts API. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;interactive-region-geochart-example-from-the-documentationhttpsdevelopersgooglecommapsdocumentationjavascriptfusiontableslayer&quot;&gt;Interactive region geochart example from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/fusiontableslayer&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;regions_div&quot; style=&quot;width: 720px; height: 400px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geocharts are rendered using SVG or VML and are great for visualizing static location-based data with markers and colors. Unfortunately for me, I needed interactive maps, so my search continued. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-maps--fusion-tableshttpsdevelopersgooglecommapsdocumentationjavascriptfusiontableslayer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/fusiontableslayer&quot;&gt;Google Maps + Fusion Tables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked around Google’s vast range of developer resources some more and came across Fusion Tables layers as part of the Google Maps JavaScript API. These are pretty cool because they render data from SQL-like tables with a RESTful API onto a Google Map. For example, if you had country population data available in Fusion Tables, you could easily visualize it by region on a map. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;examplehttpsdevelopersgooglecommapsdocumentationjavascriptexampleslayer-fusiontables-styling-of-a-google-maps-fusion-tables-layer-with-styling&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/examples/layer-fusiontables-styling&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt; of a Google Maps Fusion Tables Layer with styling&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fusion_tables.png&quot; alt=&quot;Fusion Tables layer example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you can easily add click events, which can be used to pop up infoboxes with additional data, for example. However, the problem for me was that you can only have a maximum of four different layers on a map at once, which greatly limits the ability for multiple users to create custom maps on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kartographhttpkartographorg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kartograph.org/&quot;&gt;Kartograph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these didn’t appear to be doing me any good, I searched for some non-Google alternatives and found the Kartograph platform. I didn’t delve too deeply into this, but basically it’s built on top of jQuery and a vector graphics library called &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaeljs.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël.js&lt;/a&gt; and lets you create interactive SVG maps of pretty much anything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;one-of-the-many-many-examples-of-kartograph-maps-check-out-their-showcasehttpkartographorgshowcase-for-other-cool-possibilites&quot;&gt;One of the many, many examples of Kartograph maps. Check out their &lt;a href=&quot;http://kartograph.org/showcase/&quot;&gt;showcase&lt;/a&gt; for other cool possibilites.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kartograph.png&quot; alt=&quot;German visitors to the Kartograph website in 2012&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kartograph.org/docs/kartograph.js/&quot;&gt;Read the JavaScript docs&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested, but it seems like as long as the data exist, there’s no limit to how you can visualize it. While this is great if you’re already familiar with GDAL, the amount of functionality provided seemed like overkill for my purposes, since all I needed was a simple world map with country borders. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-maps--data-layerhttpsdevelopersgooglecommapsdocumentationjavascriptdatalayer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/datalayer&quot;&gt;Google Maps + Data Layer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After experimenting with what seemed like pretty much everything, I finally realized that Google might have had what I needed this whole time. Specifically, the data layer of the Google Maps API lets you load GeoJSON data on top of a map, combining easy-to-use raw data with the built-in functionality and event handling of Google Maps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;examplehttpsdevelopersgooglecommapsdocumentationjavascriptexampleslayer-data-dynamic-of-a-google-maps-data-layer-with-dynamic-styling&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/examples/layer-data-dynamic&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt; of a Google Maps Data Layer with dynamic styling&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/data_layer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Data Layer with dynamic styling example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my application, I ended up just keeping the geographic data all in one place, rendering the same country borders for every user while letting them customize their own styling on top. This was exactly what I was looking for all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recommendation&quot;&gt;Recommendation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you just need a simple way to visualize location-based data, use a &lt;strong&gt;Google Charts Geochart&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have a large set of predetermined data to visualize and you want it to be interactive, try using a &lt;strong&gt;Google Map with a Fusion Tables layer&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want a ton of customizability and more types of visualizations you could ever need, give &lt;strong&gt;Kartograph&lt;/strong&gt; a shot. But if you’re like me and all you need are personalized, interactive maps for multiple users, go with &lt;strong&gt;Google Maps API and a GeoJSON data layer&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 22:15:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielni.github.io/2014/10/10/interactive-countries-and-regions-on-a-javascript-map/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielni.github.io/2014/10/10/interactive-countries-and-regions-on-a-javascript-map/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello world</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! Welcome to my new personal site! As of now it’s still a work in progress, but I’ll start posting some more interesting stuff pretty soon. In the meantime, check out some &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielni.github.io/projects&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; I’ve done or &lt;a href=&quot;http://danielni.github.io/&quot;&gt;talk to me&lt;/a&gt; about anything!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 16:50:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielni.github.io/2014/09/09/hello-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielni.github.io/2014/09/09/hello-world/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
